

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Project management
Team management
Trainer's training
Online training project templating
2D animation
3D modelling
Video and audio editing
Media integration
Data management using SCORM
protocol
LMS management

SOFTWARES

Articulate Storyline 360 Articulate Rise 360 Captivate 2019 Camtasia Office 360 Adobe Creative Suite

- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Premiere Pro
- After Effect

Vyond and many more

CONTACT

P: +1 514 502 9066 E: maria@octod.ca W: www.octod.ca/

DEMO

Demo: https://bit.ly/34TV1rB

MARIA KINOSHITA

LEARNING EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

ABOUT

After ten years of gaining experience in the training industry in various organizations, I specialized in online education and founded Octo D. I work with a team of seasoned specialists in the various fields required to produce quality interactive and multilingual online training modules. We work on large-scale projects with clients interested in our creativity, professionalism and the effectiveness of the content we provide.

Building on Octo D's success since its beginnings, I dedicate part of its revenues and especially a lot of my time to get involved in projects that are close to my heart. In 2018, I created Nomad Coliving, the first residence with work spaces and activities that promote peer to peer learning in Canada. We have already welcomed close to 50 entrepreneurs and self-employed workers from around the world. I am also involved in several other activities related to my fields of interest: entrepreneurship, education and sustainable development.

WORK EXPERIENCE



FOUNDER AND LEARNING EXPERIENCE DESIGNER OCTO D | 2013 - Present

- Business development
- Needs assessment
- Instructional design
- Media production



EDUCATION

MASTER IN MANAGEMENT HEC Montréal | 2008 - 2010

BACHELOR IN MEDIATIC ARTS UQAM | 2003 - 2007

WHO'S TRUSTING ME





















SOME RECENT PROJECTS

2022-23 Product School

Production of several online training course using Storyline 360 and Adobe Premiere Pro, and implementation of the courses on Teachables.

2022-23 Indigenous Primary Health Care Council (IPHCC)

Production of two 2-hour online training courses including videos, animation, gamification elements and numerous activities.

2022 Institut national de santé publique du Québec (INSPQ)

Production of two 2-hour online training courses including videos, animation, gamification elements and numerous activities. This project included six "You are the Hero" type scenarios inspired by the aesthetics of comic books.

2020 SPUR CHANGE Inter-Council Network

Production of a 3-hour online training course and implementation of a system for registering learners and their completion data using JavaScript to automate the delivery of certificates by Mailchimp.

2020 Mercer US/Canada (for Adecco, Tesla, Black & Decker, AlG, Sanofi, Volvo, Yelp, etc.)

Process optimization and accelerated production of 50 virtual exhibitions in Storyline 360 and 15 Presenter 360 files in four languages. The project managed in agile mode required the rapid implementation of procedures and the training of a team of around ten integrators and testers.

2019 Dawson College

Mediatization of a session equivalent to eight courses in two languages, i.e. thirty hours of training within a six-month production window. The training modules were created in partnership with Dawson's internal team, coached by Octo D.

2018 Canadian Red Cross

Creation of about 20 courses for the Canadian Red Cross since 2013.

Management of Moodle as well as inventory and classification of all teaching material when their main training advisor left. Coaching of the new counsellor to use Moodle on her first month of work.

2018 Skill and You

Creation of a training module in which the content is presented in a narrative mode (storytelling). Creation of a character in the image of the client's logo and a ghost, both animated with great realism using motion capture techniques. Creation of a realistic simulation of a job interview.

PAST PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

2010- 2016 Freelance training and Management Consultant

Support for some twenty companies in community, institutional and cultural sectors such as the City of Montreal, the bands Bran Van 3000 and Valaire, as well as several artists' agencies, the National Improvisation League, etc. Here are the main services performed for these clients.

- Consulting services in administration, human resources and finance;
- Optimization of management tools;
- In-house training and coaching;
- Project management;
- Coordination of human and material resources;
- Media production

2008- 2010 Founding of C@f St-Lo for Ressources Jeunesse de Saint-Laurent

Creation and management of a business focused on socio-professional reintegration for young adults who are homeless or living in shelters.

- Drafting of the business plan and marketing plan;
- Creation of the brand image and communication tools;
- Development of business partnerships and management of public relations;
- Fundraising in cash and materials worth close to \$500,000;
- Creation of a multidisciplinary team of nearly 10 people;
- Development of a training plan for employees;
- Development of a succession and continuity plan.